Contact

tyrehodges@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tyre-hodges-42373a137 (LinkedIn)

Certifications

Certified Medical-Surgical Registered Nurse (CMSRN) Basic Life Support Registered Professional Nurse

Tyre Hodges

Registered Nurse at NYU Langone Medical Center Greater New York City Area

Summary

Outstanding registered professional nurse dedicated to giving exceptional patient care while delivering a positive, compassionate experience to each client. Interfaces seamlessly with interdisciplinary professionals, clients, and families. Works well as an individual and within a team.

Experience

NYU Langone Health Registered Nurse April 2017 - Present (3 years 4 months) Greater New York City Area

Provide nursing care on a Medical/Surgical Telemetry and Step-down unit, working with a diverse patient population and wide array of health issues. Utilize the nursing process to while implementing and developing patient care plans.

Coordinate with an interdisciplinary professional team.

Advocate for patients and escalate the situation accordingly.

Delegate appropriate tasks to colleagues.

Participate in various shared governance councils.

Organize unit staffing and troubleshoot while serving charge nurse duties.

NYC Health + Hospitals
Registered Nurse - Harlem Hospital
November 2015 - April 2017 (1 year 6 months)
Greater New York City Area

Performed scrub and circulating nurse duties across multiple surgical specialties.

Ensured functioning equipment and adequate supplies for surgeries.

Preserved sterility of surgical field, and monitored sterile technique during procedures.

Collected and handled specimen.

Followed infection control protocols, including confirming sterility of instruments and supplies, verifying administration of prophylactic antibiotics, and assuring performance of surgical site prep.

Assessed patients for signs of surgical complications or distress, before, during and after procedures.

Formulated intra-operative nursing care plans.

Visiting Nurse Service of New York Nurse Scholar Intern June 2014 - August 2014 (3 months)

Greater New York City Area

Evaluated patients referred to VNSNY Home Care program to determine appropriateness of admission.

Interviewed and assessed over 20 patients per week.

Assisted in facilitation of the safe and timely transfer of patients from hospital to the care of the agency.

Visited clients in the hospital, hospice, and home settings.

Established lines of communication between the primary care provider and the home care nurse.

Utilized software to input patient information and submit insurance information to the medical biller.

Education

NYU Rory Meyers College of Nursing

Master of Science - MS, Nursing Informatics · (2020 - 2023)

City University of New York-Hunter College
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Nursing (2011 - 2015)